# **THOMAS TARTIERE**

# **Lead Software Developer**

904–1307 Harwood St, Vancouver, BC, V6E 1S7 (604) 349 8750 – thomas.tartiere@gmail.com



#### **PROFILE**

Entrepreneur mindset, thorough experience in fast-paced environments.

Strong analytical skills with solid understanding of industrial environments, SaaS development and data processing.

Strong interpersonal skills, as demonstrated through leading and collaborating in multidisciplinary teams.

Results driven project manager with proven success in completing projects on time.

Multilingual: Fluent in French, English & Spanish; basic Russian & German.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Lead Software Developer**

01/2017 to Now

Panevo, Vancouver

Lead all aspects of software development from roadmap to operation and customer support:

- Built a SaaS platform to process & visualize energy data from large industrial corporations
- Built a real time production monitoring system for downtime detection and lean manufacturing, processing millions of sensor messages per day
- Designed a utility bill management system to detect anomalies in tens of thousands of electricity, gas water & telecom bills

#### **R&D Engineer**

01/2012 to 12/2016

Enertime, Paris then Vancouver

Led the development of innovative technologies for industrial energy efficiency:

- Developed software tools for modeling and optimization of industrial systems
- Coordinated multidisciplinary teams in multi-million \$ research projects
- Published 8 conference & journal articles, 1 patent

#### **EDUCATION**

## Online (Coursera, Udacity...)

2015 to now

Completed 10+ courses on Machine Learning & DevOps

### Stanford University, USA

2009-2010

M. Sc. in Mechanical Engineering (Energy Sciences)

#### **Ecole Centrale Paris, France**

2008-2010

M. Sc in General Engineering

**Preparatory classes in Sciences, France** 2006-2008

Intensive preparation for top Engineering Schools

#### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Programming: Python, Javascript, C\C++
- Full-stack web development
  - Back-End (Django/Flask, REST API, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Redis, MQTT, PostgreSQL, MS SQL Server, Nifi)
  - Front-End (Vue.JS, JS tools)
  - DevOps (Microsoft Azure, Docker/Docker Swarm, Prometheus/Grafana, Serverless, Linux)
- Distributed systems and data intensive applications
- Data science and Machine Learning (Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn). Deep Learning (Tensor Flow, Keras)
- Energy management & Lean Manufacturing
- Project Management Professional (PMP)
- Professional Engineer (P. Eng.)
- Business development and B2B sales
- Professional written and oral communication

# **ACCOMPLISHMENTS / AWARDS**

- Rotary Foundation Ambassadorial Scholarship (2010)
- Rowing Club President, Ecole Centrale Paris (2009-2010): involved in national and international university events.
- French National Programming Competition : Finalist (2005)